Good evening.
My name is Kyle Jensen
...school management and I'm also director of entrepreneurial programs here.
Our guest tonight is Robert Martin
Who's gonna talk about SOLID principles of object oriented and Agile design
We're very lucky to have him here
... he's here at the great time for Yale
As you may know the university investing a great deal into entrepreneurship
And it's creating, I think
Or mixing with university's traditional expertise and
let's say, computer science, and a theory side and
...all sorts of great things on campus.
So, for example, two years ago I started tech bootcamp
and hack Yale(?) started
Year ago I had brought together a thousand developers
From throughout the country to the two-day hackathon
This semester
Daniel Bobby(?) changed the introduction program to course here
Which is the kind of core programming course for
non-majors to be
Mobile application development
And Daniel and I teaching together next year(?)
in the spring.
Got Computer Science 113 which in entrepreneurship in programming, we have a course on management in software development here.
At the Yale school vangan(?)
So this is to say that there's great interest at Yale in software development and
And it transcends a couple different disciplines so it's
here(?) the school of management and department of computer science it's school of engineering
and all sorts of places and across different clubs so
organizations like the Yale
entrepreneurs to Hack Yale, entrepreneurship club here
ITS, Y-Hack, all these kinds of organizations
and it's not just Yale
there is couple logos up there
that are not, I think, that are not at Yale but indicative of a activity
in this space, in a local community.
So we have to thank for the food tonight
Caniody Control(?) which is local startup and Ruby Shop filled with
wonderful hackers and developers
who are very active in http://newhaven.io which is local
developer group that I've honored to be a part of, my work with
Dan and Joel and may other people who are here
To organize a variety events for the haven.io and I'm happy to say
that the plurality of people here tonight are actually probably not
Not from Yale which I think is really important because
Traditionally Yale has this town in gown problem, right, where is not much(?)
Where is not much interaction
And I think it's a real problem, I think that it's the area which we have mutual interest and excitement
And so it's wonderful to have a events like these and we very happy to have
a Bob here to speak so
I'm gonna invite Dan to come up and
Introduce themselves and
while you needn't to introduce yourself you should just introduce Bob
Dan, I introduce you, so Dan is
Dan is a developer at Continuity Control
He has been a organizer of a
local Ruby group for many years
Organizer of haven.io
I think he's on a board of haven.io
He's essentially very active local developer
Very supportive of the local community
and I think that it's wonderful on it's how our friendship is grown in that context, so, Dan
Thank you
So (?) here (?) and I
(?)
You're hiring?(?) You joing the Sax?(?)
talk to(?)
Hello, any better?
Alright, ...projecting(?), sorry.
Alright, Dan Bernier, cat nuity(?), haven.io
Some reversion, alright, so
Like I did said, we're hiring
And we will have a little continuity, the help-ins(?), so
we do some pretty interesting things.
We aim to have a very clean code,
We have some interesting projects coming up with the machine learning
Interesting stuff like that, so
We're hiring, come talk to us.
So, software is, making software is a wired business, it's a messy business.
There are a bit of students may not have found this out yet,
because if it's just for fun, it's a lot of fun,
But when it matters, when the people paying you for the software that you're writing or people using your software
God forbid, people who's lifes depend on your software.
It's a weird business
and sometimes you can feel kind of like we're bunch of kids running around
with our shoes untied and you just hoping you don't fall down.
But luckily we have an uncle looking out for us, giving us the kick in the butt once in while when we need it
Uncle Bob has been doing quite a number of things over his career
he helped write and signed the Agile manifesto.
Which really helped the industry to rethink the way it looks at working with business people
and the way we plan software
How much we can know about the piece of software before we've built it?