And the "diamond problem" has been solved.
the "diamond problem" is simple - you get a basecl... a derivative(?)
two base classes, both of this classes have a common base class - it is the "deadly diamond of death"
and there is a huba ambiguity around that, we won't go into the details
but why didn't they resolved it, cause it had been resolved before by many other languages?
Why didn't Java resolve this?
To simplify the compiler. This is my best guess.
They were too lazy to deal with it, so they invented a horrible hack, called "interface"
And they stuck that in the language instead
?? rewiev the interface ??, interfaces are good
Interfaces are wonderful, and Interface is nothing than an abstract class with a bunch of abstract methods in it
Right? It's not some special thing
In fact the only special thing in java about in interface is what you can't do to it.
You can't inherit multiple interfaces, you can't inherit multiple classes
In to another class. Why? because the only thint that you allowed to multiple inherit is interfaces
A hack... A lazy hack...
They should not have done that. They should have solved the problem
In stead of just throwing it out
And then what happened it went to a bunch of other languages
You can tell that I'm enjoying myself, aren't you?
Ok, so. We did have inheritance of a kind in C, we were able to simulate it
But it wasn't very convinient, so what I'll do here is I will give C
half credit, I will give OO half credit for giving us
a slightly more convinient inheritance.
Ruby programmers, how much do you use inheritance?
All the time
Yea, for what?
mixins
Active record
Do you use it for polymorphism?
on ducktypes (?)
do you need to use inheritance for ducktypes?
No, no
In Ruby, in Python - dinamically typed languages
you can have polymorphism without any inheritance
in fact, all polymorphism in this languages
comes without inheritance. Inheritance is not necessary
What you use inheritance for in dinamically typed languages
is to inherit behavior and variables
but not interface
you can get all the polymorphism you wanf for free
In Java, DotNet and C++ we have to have inheritance to do polymorphism
one of the weaknesses of this languages
You have to use inheritance to get polymorphism
Ok. Which leaves us with the last of those three
Polymorphism
Did we have polymorphism in C?
Well, sort of, sort of...
in C we could to this
copy application
int C... we used integers in early C
I think there is parenthese there
Unix copy programm, vastly simplified
what does that programm do?
Ooo, did a nasty...
It does, but...
not exactly
It copies from standart input to standart output
getChar reads a character from standart input
putChar writes a character to standart output
what is standart input? It defaults to the keyboard
But it doesn't have to be the keyboard, it could be anything
putChar writes to Standart Output, which is usually the terminal
I used the word terminal, how old I am...
But it doesnt have to be the terminal, it could be anything
thosa are a polymorphic calls. getChar and putChar are a polymorphic method calls
on a class named "File" if you wish
just like any other virtual function in C++
just like any polymorphic function in Java
I have a type priority there
every IO driver is just another type
I had perfect incapsulation in C, I had reasonable inheritance in C, I could get polymorphism in C
Ow, how did that polymorphism work?
How was it that the flow of control left getChar and goit into a keyboard driver?
How that happened?
getChar was implemented in different ways and just a name is the same?
Noo, it's much more clever than than, muck more insidious
Every IO driver had a five magical functions
Every IO driver had this functions, they all had the exact same signature
READ, WRITE, OPEN, CLOSE, SEEK
If you wrote an IO driver, you had to implement those 5 functions
And the fife functions had to have the same signature
open, close, read, write, seek
The operating system will take pointers to those functions and put it into a table